ALI MURTAZA

Karachi, Pakistan.

E-Mail: - alimurtazasiddiqui17@gmail.com

Contact: - +92-337-0389343 Skype ID:- ali.murtazasiddiqui91

LinkedIn:- https://www.linkedin.com/in/ali-murtaza1991/

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Secure a responsible position in the HR department, sharing my 6 years of experience in H.R Operations & Payroll, I have certified H.R Professional with advance excel expertise (Dashboard Reporting & Power Query) and an ability to work across multiple stakeholders to further the growth of the company.

EXPERIENCE

H.R Executive (January 2019 — To Present) (Operations & Payroll)



Responsibilities: -

- Processing 18 million expenses and 600 manpower Payroll including management and nonmanagement employees.
- Operating Gratuity, P.F, Loans, advances, leave encashment, Settlement and Yearly Bonus of employees.
- o Analyze and organize Monthly, Quarterly, annually report w.r.t overtime, late assumption, Leaves, Headcount, Turnover, Manpower Production.
- Manage SESSI, EOBI contribution at the end of each month and submitted by respective Council.
- Managed Letter for salaries and coordinate with the respective individual to ensure timely payment about the salary transfer.
- o I Have an aptitude interest in numerical work, and related analysis, and the ability to handle large data.

H. R Executive (July 2014 — January-19) (H.R Operations & Payroll)



Responsibilities:

- Accountable for accurate Payroll processing of more than 1800 employees (Non-management & Contractual staff).
- o Maintained Attendance, Leave management records with respect to (AL. CL & SL) and shift roster of employees in the Oracle HRMS module.
- o Maintained employee-related records in ERP (Oracle) HRM Module and generate different reports for decision-making purposes.
- o Prepared monthly HR reports (employee turnover, late arrivals, Over Time, etc.)
- Created data loader queries for Oracle HRMS Module and that query reduced the time and efforts of any individual.
- o Prepared Leave Encashment of Management and Non-Management Staff.
- o Data Analysis using a pivot table, slicer, and Microsoft Power B.I tool.
- o Maintained Full & Final Settlement of Employees within two days.
- Excellent knowledge of MS office especially advance excel.

Assistant Accountant (May 2012 – June 2014)

(M.T ALI ENTERPRISES)

Responsibilities:

- o Worked with spreadsheets, sales, and purchase ledgers and journals.
- o Calculate and checked to make sure payments, amounts and records are correct.
- o Sorted out the incoming and outgoing daily posts and answering any queries.
- Managed petty cash transactions.

Junior Accountant (November 2008 – February 2012) (LOKHANDWALA TRADERS)

Responsibilities:

- o Post and process journal entries to ensure all business transactions are recorded.
- o Update accounts receivable and issue invoices.
- o Update accounts payable and performs reconciliations.
- o Post and process journal entries to ensure all business transactions are recorded.
- o Prepare monthly sales reports into excel spreadsheets for analysis.

EDUCATION

- B.S Information Technology (2011-2015) (PIMSAT, Karachi)
- D.A.E (Information Technology) (2007-2010) (G.C.T SITE, Karachi)
- Matriculation (Bio Science) (2006-2007)
 (Alpha Boys Secondary School, Karachi.)

COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

• Certified H.R Professional

HRPLUS (Module: Job Analysis, Talent Acquisition, KPI Based PMS, HR Policies & Procedures, Com & Benefits, Employee Engagement, Training & Development, Strategic H.R)

- Advance Course on I.R and Labor Laws
 NED University of Engineering & Technology
- Microsoft Office Specialist Excel 2016 Exams 77-727

SKILLS

1. Time Management

3. Problem solving

5. Team Work

2. Data analysis

4. Multitasking

6. Organizational